Guide to the Edwina Dumm Collection
The Ohio State University Billy Ireland Cartoon Library & Museum
- Series V: Alec the Great and other comics, 1949-1967
  Series V contains materials related to several animal characters created by Edwina Dumm, such as Alec the Great, Mr. Socrates, and Sinbad. The series contains sketches of the characters, proofs of the characters' comic strips, and a book by Edwina Dumm on drawing animals.
  - Mister Socrates unfinished drawing and sketches, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 2)
  - Mr. Socrates negatives of photographic proofs, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 10)
  - Alec the Great Enlargement, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 12)
  - Alec the Great sample release proofs, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 18)
  - Alec the Great proofs, 1949-1967 (Box FED 6, Folder 19-22)
    Proofs are primarily from 1949, 1954, 1955, and 1967.
  - Alec the Great introduction material, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 32)
  - Dog statue, possibly Sinbad, undated (Box FED 6, Piece 48)
  - Sinbad clippings from Life magazine, [1930s] (Box FED 7, Folder 1)
  - Alec the Great calendar and unique Tippie material (unpublished round songbook), [1940s]-1975 (Box FED 10, Folder 18)
  - Alec the Great book ideas by Edwina and Robert Dumm, [1930s]-1980 (Box FED 10, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous animal sketches and drawings, 1980 (Box FED 10, Folder 20)
  - Book idea, How to Draw Dogs and Cats by Edwina, undated (Box FED 10, Folder 26)
- Series VI: Photographs, [1880s]-1987
  Series VI contains photographs of Edwina Dumm or the property of Edwina Dumm. The photographs are publicity photographs and personal photographs, including photographs of cartoon exhibitions. There are also photographs of the family of Edwina Dumm, which had been displayed in her apartment.
  - Photograph of Edwina Dumm taken by Frank Pauer, October 25, 1987 (Box FED 2, Folder 60)
  - Photographs of Edwina Dumm, [1930s-1940s] (Box FED 6, Folder 1)
  - Photographs from Montreal, Quebec, Canada exhibit, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 24)
  - Box of assorted photographic slides, undated (Box FED 7, Folder 11)
  - Binder of photographic negatives (people, places, things, etc.), 1974-1975 (Box FED 8, Folder 4)
  - King Features photographs of Edwina and her pets, [1930s-1940s] (Box FED 10, Folder 2)
  - Photographic negatives, [1980s] (Box FED 10, Folder 25)
  - Photograph of people in canoes on a lake, from Edwina Dumm's apartment, [1880s-1890s] (Box FED 11, Folder 5)
  - Photograph of men and boys beside a cabin, from Edwina Dumm's apartment, [1880s-1890s] (Box FED 11, Folder 6)
  - Photograph of three men and a boy, from Edwina Dumm's apartment, June 6, 1883 (Box FED 11, Folder 7)
  - Photograph of man in costume, believed to be Frank Edwin Dumm, Edwina's father, [1880s-1890s] (Box FED 11, Folder 8)
  - Photograph of costumed woman and man, believed to be Frank Edwin Dumm, Edwina's father, [1880s-1890s] (Box FED 11, Folder 9)
  - Photograph of costumed woman and man, believed to be Frank Edwin Dumm, Edwina's father, [1880s-1890s] (Box FED 11, Folder 10)
  - Photograph of costumed woman and man, believed to be Frank Edwin Dumm, Edwina's father, [1880s-1890s] (Box FED 11, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Sheet music, musical scripts, and other Helen Thomas collaborations, 1943-1975
  Series VII contains records of the collaborative works between Edwina Dumm and songwriter and composer Helen Thomas and other sheet music. The series includes examples of sheet music illustrated by Edwina Dumm and featuring her characters. The series also contains drafts of plays created by Dumm and Thomas.
  - Sheet music with illustrations by Edwina Dumm, words and music by Helen Thomas, 1943-1950 (Box FED 2, Folder 63)
    Sheet music titles are: "Shelter Lullaby," "Tippie and the Circus," "Tippie's Christmas Carol," "Tippie's Love Song," "Tippie and the Hurdy-Gurdy," "Tippie's Hallowe'en Serenade," "The Christmas Tree"
  - "Tippie's Dinner Song" songbook drawing negatives and "Tippie's Hallowe'en Serenade" cover, [1940s] (Box FED 6, Folder 9)
  - Sheet music with artwork by Edwina and words and music by Helen Thomas, 1943-1950 (Box FED 6, Folder 26)
    Song titles are "Shelter Lullaby," "Tippie's Love Song," "Tippie and the Circus," "The Christmas Tree," "Tippie's Hallowe'en Serenade," "Tippie's Christmas Carol," and "Tippie and the Hurdy-Gurdy."
  - Script of Chance Meeting with Animal Friends by Helen Thomas and Edwina, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 28)
  - Sheet music of "When You Come Home Someday" by Helen Thomas, 1943 (Box FED 6, Folder 31)
  - Letter from King Features Syndicate, about the "Tippie's Love Song", October 19, 1949 (Box FED 6, Folder 34)
  - Sheet music, "I Love to Read the Funnies" by Perry Alexander and "Woody " Frisino, 1945 (Box FED 6, Folder 35)
    The song lyrics have a mention of Tippie
  - Plays written by Edwina Dumm and Helen Thomas, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 39-40)
  - Songbook of "Tippie's Tunes" with 33 1/3" LPs, undated (Box FED 8, Folder 5)
  - Watercolor songbook covers by Edwina, [1940s]-1975 (Box FED 10, Folder 14)
- Series VIII: Oral History Interview, February 15, 1985
  Series VIII contains audio recordings and transcripts of an oral history interview conducted with Edwina Dumm from 1985.
  - Oral History Interview, February 15, 1985 (Box FED 2, Folder 58)
    Contains 2 audio cassettes, one as an archival copy, the other as a use copy, and 2 compact discs of the oral history interview.
    Oral history is recorded on audio cassette and compact disc.
  - Transcript of oral history interview, February 15, 1985 (Box FED 2, Folder 59)
- Series IX: Correspondence, 1935-1983
  Series IX contains a variety of the personal and professional correspondence of Edwina Dumm. The series contains Christmas cards and letters, including some which were never mailed. There is business correspondence with the George Matthew Adams Service and Oriolo Films Studio Inc. as well.
  - Christmas Card by Edwina Dumm, undated (Box FED 2, Folder 61)
  - Employee Christmas greetings, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Al Felden, 1979 (Box FED 6, Folder 8)
  - Christmas cards designed by Edwina, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 14)
  - Christmas cards written but never sent, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 16)
  - Cards from other people, [1980] (Box FED 6, Folder 17)
  - George Matthew Adams Service correspondence, 1935-1968 (Box FED 10, Folder 4)
  - Oriolo Films Studio Inc. correspondence and Edwina Productions information, 1981-1983 (Box FED 10, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1948-1983 (Box FED 10, Folder 9)
- Series X: Biographical Material, Memorabilia, and Miscellaneous Items, 1916-1986
  Series X contains mostly personal artifacts of Edwina Dumm, such as calendars, articles about her and her characters, and various awards and certificates she received. The series also contains some of her personal notes and papers. The series contains the personal diaries of Edwina Dumm, spanning several decades later in her life, from 1960 until 1986.
  - Biographical excerpts, 1916-1985 (Box FED 2, Folder 62)
  - Cartoons Magazine, with a profile of Edwina Dumm and a comic by Billy Ireland, January 1917 (Box FED 2, Folder 64)
  - "Edwina's Famous Dogs" advertising header, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 7)
  - Calendar, 1976 (Box FED 6, Folder 11)
  - Life magazine with Edwina cover drawing, January 10, 1930 (Box FED 6, Folder 23)
  - Golden key to the National Cartoonists Society Hall of Fame, April 17, 1978 (Box FED 6, Folder 25)
  - Loose pages from scripts, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 29)
  - Circus Fantasy with Susie, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 30)
  - Sketch of animals in the jungle by Edwina, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 33)
  - Article clippings, 1947-1978 (Box FED 6, Folder 36)
  - Short stories written by Edwina Dumm, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 37)
  - Short stories by Edwina Dumm, undated (Box FED 6, Folder 38)
  - Long Term Care for the Aged television special proposal, 1980 (Box FED 6, Folder 45)
  - Red and gold "CARTOONIST" sash, [1978] (Box FED 6, Piece 46)
  - Hagar the Horrible statue made by Graham Halky, July 12, 1978 (Box FED 6, Piece 47)
  - Poster from Al Felden to Edwina, 1978-1979 (Box FED 7, Piece 6)
  - Poster from the Comic Art Show, 1983 (Box FED 7, Piece 7)
  - Samantha's Note Book drafts and sketches, 1974-1976 (Box FED 10, Folder 1)
  - Various photocopies, undated (Box FED 10, Folder 6)
  - Book and magazine covers, some featuring Sinbad, 1925-1983 (Box FED 10, Folder 8)
    Book covers include The Comics, by Coulton Waugh, Sinbad: A Dog's Life and Sinbad Again by Edwina. Magazine covers include Farm & Fireside, Life, and Good Old Days.
  - Untitled "how to" book by Bob Dumm, illustrations by Edwina, undated (Box FED 10, Folder 15)
  - Cartoon syndicate and exhibition catalogs, 1948-1983 (Box FED 10, Folder 16)
  - Membership certificates to the Society of Illustrators and the National Cartoonists Society, 1953-1969 (Box FED 10, Folder 17)
  - Articles in comic encyclopedia about Edwina and her characters, 1976 (Box FED 10, Folder 21)
  - King Feature Syndicate congratulations for award winners, 1978 (Box FED 10, Folder 22)
  - Diaries of Edwina Dumm, 1963-1971 (Box FED 12, Folder 1-13)
    FED Box 12, Folder 1 spans March 18, 1963 to July 10, 1963. FED Box 12, Folder 2 spans January 20, 1964 to June 2, 1964. FED Box 12, Folder 3 spans June 6, 1964 to October 23, 1964. FED Box 12, Folder 4 spans June 3, 1965 to November 8, 1965. FED Box 12, Folder 5 spans November 9, 1965 to April 30, 1966. FED Box 12, Folder 6 spans April 2, 1966 to October 15, 1966. FED Box 12, Folder 7 spans October 16, 1966 to April 1, 1967. FED Box 12, Folder 8 spans September 30, 1967 to February 11, 1968. FED Box 12, Folder 9 spans July 22, 1968 to January 27, 1969. FED Box 12, Folder 10 spans January 27, 1969 to April 1, 1969. FED Box 12, Folder 11 spans September 4, 1969 to November 21, 1969. FED Box 12, Folder 12 spans June 8, 1970 to September 11, 1970. FED Box 12, Folder 13 spans September 12, 1970 to March 1971.
  - Diaries of Edwina Dumm, 1971-1986 (Box FED 13, Folder 1-12)
    FED Box 13, Folder 1 spans July 10, 1971 to January 30, 1972. FED Box 13, Folder 2 spans January 30, 1972 to July 19, 1972. FED Box 13, Folder 3 spans November 28, 1972 to May 24, 1973. FED Box 13, Folder 4 spans May 25, 1973 to December 19, 1973. FED Box 13, Folder 5 spans December 19, 1973 to August 1, 1974. FED Box 13, Folder 6 spans November 1, 1974 to July 16, 1975. FED Box 13, Folder 7 spans July 18, 1975 to December 16, 1975. FED Box 13, Folder 8 spans December 17, 1975 to February 20, 1977. FED Box 13, Folder 9 spans February 20, 1977 to February 12, 1978. FED Box 13, Folder 10 spans November 20, 1978 to November 30, 1979. FED Box 13, Folder 11 spans December 1 1979 to January 24, 1981. FED Box 13, Folder 12 spans January 28, 1981 to July 5, 1986. FED Box 13, Folder 12 was donated from the Estate of Nancy Coe, by Amy Bickers, on August 11, 2008.